ALLEN WELCH

Atlanta, GA (678) 910-6491



Developer with a background in research and online education using various Learning Management Systems. Over 5 years in multiple leadership positions within my department acting as mentor/supervisor with a focus on collaboration. Detailed-oriented and committed to developing creative and efficient solutions through the use of technology.

Technical Skills:

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, Node.js, ReactJS, VueJS, Express, MySQL, C#, Bootstrap, Semantic-UI, Materialize, SASS, Media Queries, JSON, Firebase, MongoDB, GitHub, Heroku, and various APIs.

Projects:

Movie-Vue | VueJS, MySQL, Node, Express, JSON Web Tokens | <u>GitHub</u> | <u>Live</u>
Responsive CRUD application using the Movie DB allowing users to browse, search, and add movies to a watchlist.

- Created search component to utilize The Movie DB API
- Connection to MySQL DB to hold user information including user wathclist.
- Used JSON web tokens to authenticate user sign in/sign out.

Cicerowned | ReactJS, MongoDB, Express, Node | GitHub | Live

Responsive educational app for individuals studying for their Cicerone Certifications built on MERN stack.

- Setup file structure including client and backend server using Node and Express
- Connected Search feature to Untapped API and Contact feature to Email.js
- Created application's Flashcard & CustomCard components and pages as well as user Sign-In component utilizing Auth0 authentication services.

Cryptoverse | Node, Express.js, Sequelize, JSON Web Tokens | <u>GitHub</u> | <u>Live</u> A learning and comparison application for newcomers in the world of cryptocurrency.

- Created server and routing using Express.js
- Established secure user authentication using JSON Web Tokens
- Created all verified queries to user data including POST, GET, and PUT requests.

Experience:

EY Studios- Kennesaw, GA | August 2018 – present

- Web Developer
 - o Creating customized features and styling for numerous eCommerce store themes on the BigCommerce & Shopify platforms.
 - o Working primarily on the BigCommerce platform using the Stencil CLI and Object model.
 - o Languages/Tools: HTML5, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, jQuery, Handlebars, & AJAX

Trilogy Education- Atlanta, GA | November 2018 – present

• Teaching Assistant for Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp at Georgia Tech.

Georgia Connections Academy- Duluth, GA | July 2012-August 2018

- AP Coordinator, Social Studies Department Chair, and Teacher (Grades 9-12)
 - o Manage Social Studies team with regards to student performance data, student contact and logs, and student remediation plans as well as organize AP exam registration and payments.

Education:

Georgia Institute of Technology - Atlanta, GA | Full Stack Web Development Certification Georgia State University - Atlanta, Ga. | Master of Arts History (Concentration: World History) Kennesaw State University - Kennesaw, Ga. | Bachelor of Science History Education

Email: allenjwelch@gmail.com GitHub: https://github.com/allenjwelch

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/allen-welch-659320b2

Portfolio: https://allenjwelch.github.io/portfolio/